根据真实事件改编
片名：《黑皮书》
<Black Book>
1956年10月 以色列
Israel, October 1956
好，各位 我们将在这个集体农庄稍做逗留
We will now make a short stop in what is called a kibbutz
请在15分钟后回车上集合 尽情参观吧
Be back in the bus in 15 minutes. Enjoy your visit.
- 我去照张像 - 好
(Ronnie) I'll make a photograph.
您打扰我们上课了 您可以观看，但请不要拍照
You are disturbing the lesson. You may watch, but not make pictures.
我可以讲希伯来语 但您会说荷兰语？
I speak hebrew. But you speak dutch?
你不是来自海牙的 艾莉丝·弗里斯吗？
Aren't you Ellis de Vries from The Hague?
罗妮？
Ronnie?
你怎么会在这里？
El… What are you doing here?
- 我住在这里，这是我的祖国啊 - 你是犹太人？
I live here, this is my country. - Are you jewish?
- 你来以色列干吗啊？ - 陪我丈夫来的
What are you doing in Israel? accompanying my husband.
就是他，戴衣领那个
Him, with that collar.
他叫乔治，他突然间信奉基督了 医生说是因为受到了战火的洗礼
George. He suddenly 'got religion'. Because of the war, the doctor says.
一天到晚谈着耶稣，没有罪恶之类 所以现在我的夜晚美丽安静
So:a lot of Jesus and no sins like that. It's nice and quiet at night.
上一次见到和你在一起的 不是个加拿大人吗？
The last man i saw you with, wasn't he a Canadian
就是他啊，我的加拿大男人
That's him . That's my Canadian.
乔治！乔治！这是我荷兰的朋友 战争时认识的
George. A friend from Holland, from the war.
你怎么跑到这里来隐居了呢？
How the hell did you end up here?
大家快些，我们下一站将是伽百农
Next stop is  Kapernaum.
那是耶稣第一次复活的地方
This is where Jesus performed his first healing miracle.
亲爱的再见，我会给你写信的 给你寄照片，再见艾莉丝！
Bye sweetheart. I'll write. I'll send pictures. Bye Ellis.
我现在叫瑞秋·罗森塔尔 我结婚了！
Rachel Rosenthal. I am married.
写下来，瑞秋·罗森塔尔 地址呢？
Write down, Rachel Rosenthal Address?
- 斯坦恩集体农庄 - （希伯来语）再见！希伯来语是这么说的吧
De kibbutz Stein. - Shalom.That's what it's called isn't Shalom?
（希伯来语）再见！
Shalom-
1944年9月 荷兰
Holland,  September 1944
耶稣说… 世界之光…
And Jesus said.. Light of the world…
生命之光…
light of life…
洋捷，斯汀捷 今天轮到你们两个
Jantje. Stientje. You're up today.
- 早上好，捷普科马太太 - 早上好
-  Good morning, mrs. Tjepkema. -  Good morning.
早上好，孩子们
Good morning, children.
- 早上好，小姐 - 早上好，瑞秋
Good morning, miss - Good morning, Rachel
我们说过不要再叫瑞秋了 记住没？不要再这么叫
We promised not to say Rachel anymore, remember? Never
天放晴了 今晚把马厩清扫干净
It's clearing up. Tonight I want the stables clean.
- 好的，老板 - 都快坐好！
alright, boss. At your seats, go.
父亲，你能做个祷告吗？
Father, could you do a prayer?
我们的客人也许新学了一段祷告词
Our guest probably learned a new text.
好，大家闭上眼睛
Good, close your eyes.
耶稣再次对他们说： 我是世界之光
And jesus spoke again to them: I am the light of the world.
跟随我的人，不会步入黑暗 而将获得生命之光
Who will follow me, shall not walk in darknes…
阿门
…but will have the light of life. - Amen.
Amen.
很好，没有任何小错误 斯汀捷，给她拿个盘子
Beautiful, and no slip of the tongue. Stientje, give her a plate.
如果犹太人听从了耶稣的教诲
If the jews had listened to Jesus…
他们就不会受这么多苦难了
…then they wouldn't have had all this suffering. Then again…
开始吃吧
please begin.
给
Here.
嘿，姑娘！禁止听英语歌曲！
Hey, you there, girl. English music is forbidden.
不过不穿衣服的姑娘例外
But not for naked girls
你真没趣，吓到我了 我以为是德国佬呢
You're not funny. You scared me. I thought you were a kraut.
那我怎么补偿你呢？
How can I make it up to you?
让我上船
Have me on the boat.
- 我也想要支香烟 - 好！
A ciggarette like that, i'd like as well. - Jawohl.
- 那些疯子在干什么？ - 丢掉压舱物，利于爬升
What's that crazy guy doing? - Getting rid of ballast, so he can ascend.
趴下！
Get down.
- 你干吗去？！ - 那是我住的藏身处
What are you going to do? - That's my hideout.
等下！看，德国佬
Wait. look: Germans.
你不能回去，跟我来！
You can't go back, come.
好好吃吧，小伙子
(unknown voice) enjoy your meal, boy.
嗨，别紧张，小子
(ROB:) Hey, take it easy, boy.
＂阳光之下，总有一个他＂
# there's always one beneath the sun
＂让你牵挂，那种感觉…＂
# who's bound to make you feel that way
录音机里的声音…
That voice on the record…
- 那是你！ - 曾经是
That's you. - That was me.
很久了，那时战争还没开始
In the old days. Before the war.
刚唱一次 然后就要把嘴巴闭上了
First you sing, then you have to keep your mouth shut.
给，我爸爸给我们抓的
Here, my dad caught these for us.
他真好
That's sweet of him.
把炉子点上好吗？
Will you light the stove?
- 真精致 - 送给你
Nice thing. - You can keep it.
- 真的？ - 当作你救我的纪念品
Really? - a souvenir for you who saved me
你真好
How sweet.
谢谢
Thank you.
- 至少还有好的一面 - 什么意思？
With a positive side effect. - What do you mean?
现在我不用再靠 念圣经来得到食物了
Now I don't have to spit anymore bible texts to get any food.
嘘！
Ssshhhh..
汽车 汽油发动机的声音
A car. It's a gasoline engine.
斯坦恩小姐？
Miss Stein?
瑞秋·斯坦恩？
Rachel Stein?
我知道你在这里
I know you're here.
德国人在烧毁的农场里 找到了你的护照
The germans have found your pass at the burnt out farm.
舵手马尔德因科先生 德国佬知道你当时在附近
Helmsman Maalderink, the krauts know you were in the neighbourhood.
他们记下了你的船号
They wrote down the number of your sail.
我不明白
Says who?
别装了
Come on.
德国人也是人 又不是傻子
one plus one is two, even for the krauts.
一个藏匿的犹太女人 不见了…
a hidden jewish woman dissappears…
…而你是附近唯一的水手
…and the only sailor around to help is you.
- 你来这里干吗？ - 来警告你
What are you doing here? - To warn you.
党卫队保安部很快就会来逮捕她 押送到波兰集中营
Soon the SD will come and arrest her for transport to Poland.
而你和你的家人 将会因为帮助犹太人而被投入监狱
And you and your family, will be put in jail, for aiding jews.
你从哪里得到消息的？
How did this news reach you?
德国佬的报告送到了 海牙当地警局的手中
The police report of the krauts landed in the hands of the The Hague police.
- 他们把报告给了我们 - “你们”？“你们”是谁？
They  gave it to us. - Us? Who's us?
我们就是我们 令人高兴的是，荷兰还是有不少好警察的
Us are us. Be happy, that there's so many good cops, in Holland.
我只想告诉你们一件事 躲起来，马上！
I wanted to tell you one thing. Hide. NOW.
晚安
Good night.
- 还不清楚吗？ - 你得帮我和罗布藏起来
Wasn't I clear enough? - You have to help me and Rob to go into hiding.
你所说的“你们”是抵抗组织，你和 他们是一起的，你能帮我们，对吧？
With 'us' you mean the resistance. You're with them. So you can help us, right?
- 也许吧，但是那很危险 - 我们愿意冒这个险
Maybe yes, but it's dangerous. - We'll take that risk.
请不要让我们失望 求求你
Please don't let us down. Please?
有条逃生路线，要穿过俾斯伯士河 我可以带你们去解放区
There's an escape route, through the Biesbosch. I can get you to liberated territory.
穿越国境，现在？ 真是疯了
Cross country, NOW? That's madness
再过几周英国士兵就来了 荷兰就将被解放了
In a few weeks the tommy's will be here and Holland will be liberated
你的英国兵早在 阿纳姆就被击溃了
Your Tommy's have been cut to pieces at Arnhem
选择吧，要么跟我来 要么你们自己照顾自己
Choose: come with me or, take care of yourself
等一下，我们跟你去
Wait. we'll come.
准备一下，明天下午2点 我来接你们
Be ready tomorrow, 2 'o' clock. I'll pick you up-
不要带过多东西 但是要保证能坚持一阵
Don't bring too much, but make sure you can hold out for a while.
就是这里了 我在拐角等你
It's here. I'll wait on the corner.
- 什么事？ - 我来见律师
Yes? - I'm here for the notary.
我是瑞秋·斯坦恩
I am Rachel Stein.
跟我来 我带你去
follow me, I will check for you.
威姆，有个叫斯坦恩的姑娘找你 你有空吗？
(Mrs. Smaal:) Wim, there's girl called Stein here. Do you have a moment?
我丈夫现在可以见你了
My husband can see you now.
- 斯马尔 - 瑞秋·斯坦恩
Smaal. -  Rachel Stein.
我父亲告诉过我 如果有麻烦可以找您帮忙
My father said, to call for your aid, whenever I'll be in trouble.
每个年轻姑娘都可以 自称是瑞秋·斯坦恩
Every young lady, can call herself Rachel Stein.
那是我父母和弟弟
My parents and my little brother.
我能帮你什么忙呢，瑞秋？
What can I do for you Rachel?
我的藏身处被炸掉了 证件，东西全没有了
My hideout is blown up. I have no papers, nothing.
我有个机会摆渡去解放区
I have a chance to cross over to liberated area.
- 真的吗？ - 是的
Really? -  Yes.
我需要些钱来维持生计
I will be needing money to live.
多少？
How much?
最少可以维持一年
At least enough, to last me a year.
10万？
100 grand?
不，那不可能
No, that's impossible.
一半？
Half of it?
如果可以，最好是美元或珠宝 我不想占过多地方
In dollars and jewels, if possible. I don't want it to take up too much space.
你得在收据上签个字
You'll have to sign the receipt.
我需要以后向你父亲说明
I have to justify this to your father later on.
您知道我父母在哪里吗？
Do you know where my parents are?
不知道 也不想知道
No, I don't know and I don't want to know.
- 在哪里签？ - 这里
Where do I sign? - Here.
- 等下 - 你不要清点一下？
Hold on. You don't want to check first?
不了，我相信您
No, I trust you.
瑞秋，你不能盲目相信别人 那种时代已经过去了
Rachel, you can't trust someone blindly. Those times are over.
请出示证件
Checkpoint: Show me you papers.
范·亨，党卫队保安部 押载被捕的犹太人
Van Gein, from the SD, with a load of arrested jews.
十个
10 pieces
好的，可以通过了 旅途愉快
Check. You may continue. Have a good trip.
希特勒万岁
Heil Hitler.
出来吧
Come out.
我们走
Let's go.
瑞秋，瑞秋！
Rachel. Rachel.
马科斯，那是我弟弟
Max. That's my little brother.
- 我们也在 - 妈妈
We're here too. - Mum.
我的孩子
my girl.
嘘…小声些 来，来
Sshh.. Be quiet, come, come
- 你们怎么到这里来的 - 通过他
How did you get here? - Throug. him.
- 他说你准备渡河 - 然后我们也想过去
He said, you were going to cross. - Then we wanted to go too.
这是罗布，帮助过我
This is Rob, he helped me.
嗨
Hi.
不要推挤，小心些 向前
Don't push, be careful, go forward.
过去，坐下
Come and sit.
请坐下
Please, sit.
快些，小伙子
Hurry up boy.
他刚动过手术
He's just had an operation.
4天前刚做的手术
4 days ago.
对不起，我不知道
I'm sorry, I didn't know.
麻烦你撤掉木板
Could you throw away the plank?
你不和我们一起？
You're not joing us?
不了，这里开始船长接手
No, the skipper will take it from here.
一路顺风
safe travels
太太，请摘掉它 夜里太显眼
Lady, take that off. It glows too much in the dark.
我连睡觉都带着的
I keep it on even in my sleep.
那就把领子系紧些 德国佬眼睛很灵
Then move up your collar. The krauts see everything.
我们出发
Let's go.
看，姜饼，聚会上剩下来的 现在派上用场了
Look: gingerbread. Saved it for a party. That means now.
你出什么事了？
What happened to you?
急性阑尾炎 他差点不能和我们走
Acute appendix infection. He almost couldn't join us.
我的律师及时给我们找了大夫
My notary found us doctor just in time.
- 大夫偷偷地帮他做了手术 - 就在厨房的桌子上
He operated him secretly. - On the kitchen table.
斯马尔先生知道你们在哪里吗？
Did mr. Smaal know where you were?
当然，他给了我们藏身处的地址
Of course. He gave us the address of the hideout.
他坚持对我说他不知道，奇怪
Odd, he kept repeating he didn't know.
不，他只是谨慎
No, careful.
- 你们的藏身处在哪里？ - 在一无聊的杂货店主家的阁楼里
Where was your hideout? - In the attic of a boring grocer's man
- 一个社会主义者，但还算不错 - 不过还是布鲁塞尔好
A socialist, but still good. -  but Brussels is better.
- 现在我们不会再分开了，对吧？ - 是啊
Now, we'll never be separated again, right? - right.
为什么我们向东边开？
Why are we going east?
你怎么知道？
How can you tell?
战前 我当过一艘大船上的舵手
I used to be helmsman on a big ship. Before the war.
战前我在荷-美航线上工作 我正在弯曲前进
Before the war I was on the Holland- America line. I am zigzagging
很好
Excellent.
下车 打开货舱
Get out. Show me your cargo.
- 打开 - 是个死人
Open up. -  But she's dead.
- 她得了很厉害的病 - 斑疹伤寒症
but it's a very bad disease. -  Typhus.
打开！
Open it.
关上吧
Close it.
天啊，我差点窒息了
Man, I almost choked.
我们从没被抱怨过
We never get any complaints.
至少留了一厘米的空隙 你看
At least a centimetre of space. Look.
- 不能再宽了，否则会被注意到 - 不，我是说下雨
Can't do any wider, otherwise they'll notice. - No, I mean in the rain.
我很难保持脸不动
I could hardly keep my face still.
来
Come.
你可以在这里清洗一下
You can clean yourself up over there.
给，用这个
Here, use this.
我真不知道该怎么答谢你们
I don't know, how I will ever be able to thank you.
- 你可以松开这个… - 你可以走了，约普
You could untie these… Take a hike, Joop.
应该感谢找到你的那个人
Instead thank the people who found you…
没通知党卫队保安部 而是告诉了我们
for warning us instead of warning the SD.
我们要染一下你的头发
We'll paint that.
爸爸
Dad-
凯普斯
Kuipers.
艾莉丝·弗里斯
Ellis de Vries.
你会习惯这个名字的 身份证怎么样？
You'll get used to the name. Do you have a good ID?
没问题，爸爸，比真的还像
All fine, dad. More than real.
好的
Yes.
- 以前做过饭没有？ - 我常在家里做饭，犹太人的饭菜
Did you ever do any cooking? - Yes, i used to at home, kosher.
这个就没有必要了吧
There's no demand for that anymore.
- 对不起 - 你可以留在这里
Sorry. - You can stay here.
但是你得工作
But you'll have to work.
越累越好
The harder, the better.
她家里的人被党卫队杀害了
Her whole family was murdered, by the SS.
总有一天，我们会报仇的 艾莉丝
Some time, we'll get back to them, Ellis.
五个月后
five month later
艾莉丝，过来一下
Ellis, come here.
我们需要一个替补 你可以做一个替补吗？
We need a substitute. Could you be a replacement.
- 工作就是工作 - 即使是危险的工作？
Work is work. - Even if it's dangerous?
我还有什么可以失去的呢？
What do I have to lose?
你的生命
Your life.
- 她明天和我一起去？ - 是的
She'll travel with me tomorrow? - Yes.
新情报员，艾莉丝
The new courier, Ellis
- 我是汉斯 - 艾莉丝
I am Hans. - Ellis.
请坐
Have a seat.
好，每个人都知道程序了 凯普斯小组去应付技术方面
Ok, everybody knows the procedure. The group Kuipers handles the technical side.
- 你好 - 你好
Hello. - Hello.
…我们提供掩护
.. we as KP will give cover.
- 他几点到？ - 七点半
At what time he'll arrive? - 7:30
- 风向呢？ - 北-北-西
Wind direction? - North- north- west.
约普，你打头阵 南-南-东
Then you'll take the lead, Joop: south- south- east
- 红灯 - 你待在200米处，基斯
Red. - You stay at 200 metres, Kees.
没其它的了？ 我可不是杰西·欧文斯（著名短跑运动员）
No further: I am not Jesse Owens.
- 蓝灯，基斯 - 我负责发信号
Blue, Kees. - And I give the signs.
还有其它问题么？ 把松子酒递给我
Any further questions? Then pass on the gin.
我做什么工作呢？
And what's my job in this boys club?
你扮作我的未婚妻 适时地亲吻几下
You can play my fiancee. Just kissing around somewhat.
你们扮作夫妇 这样德国佬就不会过多注意你们
You'll be playing a couple. So the krauts won't be paying attention.
只是亲吻？
Just kissing? That's all?
小伙子们
Boys.
为了女王！
To the queen.
为了威廉敏娜（荷兰女王），蒂姆 你这个共产主义佬
To Wilhelmina, Tim. You old communist.
干杯！
Cheers.
还有一分钟，我们开始
One minute to go. Let's begin.
好了，你能拿一下么？
Okay, can you take this?
巧克力 有2年没吃到过了
Chocolate. Haven't had this for 2 years.
艾莉丝，你明天携带这个箱子 小心些，里面有无线电装置
Ellis, you'll be carrying this tomorrow. Be careful, there's radio equipment in there.
音乐，太好了 我们是要跳舞么？
Music, nice. Are we going to swing?
是一个接收机
A transmitter receiver.
我要去党卫队保安部的 总部里放置一个窃听器
I am going to plant a microphone in the head office of the SD.
- 但那里防卫很严，不是吗？ - 我是电话公司的维修技术员
But that's heavily guarded, right? - I am a maintenance technician at the phone company.
德国佬一直需要我们 我可以自由进出，没问题
The krauts need us all the time. I can walk in and out, no problem.
一切都准备好了 就在等这个呢
Everything's prepared. I was just waiting for this.
- 我的东西也在里面吗？ - 这里
Is my stuff in there too? - Here.
我不能拿着它过街
I can't take this across the street.
上面写着英语“小心搬运”
'Handle with care' it says.
办公室里还有些手提箱
There's still some suitcases left in the office.
开始装货，伙计们
Start loading up, guys.
举起手来！ 不许动！
Hands up. Don't move.
我的上帝，我们杀了5个人 我们都做了些什么啊？
Oh my god, we took 5 lives. What have we done?
不是他们死就是我们死，提欧
It was them or us, Theo.
开始装车，我们得马上离开 我去看着外面
Let's load up, we have to leave. I'll check outside.
天哪，汉斯真是个冷血杀手
Goddamn. He's such a cold one, Hans.
- 他是最棒的神射手 - 如果他没击中…
He's a top marksman. - And if he had missed…
他不会失手 汉斯是“爱国者”里最好的射手
He never misses. Hans was the best marksman of Pro Patria.
- 那是什么？ - 一个学生射击俱乐部
What's that? - A student shooting club.
学生神射手俱乐部 汉斯，玛登和我都是会员
THE student marksman club. Hans, Maarten and me were members.
我们一起工作 帮助犹太人
And we work together for helping the jews.
汉斯很了不起 他能帮你完成任何事
Hans is great, he'll get you through anything.
没发现德国佬 他们应该正忙着自己的事呢
No Kraut to be seen. They were working on their own.
脱下他们的军装 我们可以利用每样东西
Take off their uniforms. We can use everything.
我们可以给他们 一个基督教式的埋葬
We'll have to them a christian burial.
哦，是吗？ 这里有很多深坑，提欧
Oh yeah? There are lots of deep holes here, Theo.
你可以把他们都仍进去
You can throw'em in there by yourself.
那是我的枪，你在想什么啊
That's my gun. What did you think.
你又怎么知道我在想事情
What did you think, I was thinking?
检查！把证件都准备好
Check. Keep your ID's ready.
我们是恋人，对么？
We're in love right?
好吧…现在开始
Well.. here it goes.
打开所有的箱子
Open all suitcases.
我开枪引开他们，你去拉紧急制动 跳车逃跑，不要想其它的事
I'll shoot. You pull the emergency brake. Leave the train and run. Can't think of anything else.
离我远点，你这个混蛋
Stay away from me, you dirty bastard.
（德语）你好
(German:) good day.
- 可以帮你吗？ - 谢谢
Can I help you? - Thank you.
很重吧？
Heavy, huh?
漂亮女士可不应该提这么重的箱子
Beautiful ladies, should not carry heavy bags.
那是我的唱片和留声机
My records and my phonograph.
- 谢谢 - 你很喜欢音乐？
Thank you. -  You like music, very much?
- 那是我的职业 - 战前我是名歌手
That's my job. I used to be a singer, before the war.
- 艾莉丝·弗里斯 - 路德维希·蒙茨
Ellis de Vries. - Ludwig Müntze
打开你的箱子，证件
Open your suitcase. Papers.
很精彩吗？
Exciting?
非常精彩，对我来说
Very exciting. For me that is.
邮票啊 我从小就喜欢这个
Postage stamps. I loved those as a child.
- 这些都是异国邮票 - 我从6岁就开始收集邮票了
all those far away countries. - I collect them since I was six.
这可能正是我学习地理的原因
Probably why I studied geography.
检查
Inspection.
你没看到我正忙吗？ 去查下一个
Can't you see I'm busy? Move along.
是，上尉
Yes, captain.
我可以看看吗？ 我保证很小心
Can I look? I'll be very gentle.
波兰…法国…
Polski… France…
我总会收集 我驻扎过的国家的邮票
I always collect the countries where I am stationed.
首先是波兰，然后法国 现在这里
First Poland, then France and now here.
你在我们的女王这里停下来了
You've stopped with our queen.
荷属印度群岛的 威廉敏娜邮票
The Wilhelmina stamps from the dutch Indies.
我不知道是否还能够收集全
I don't know if I'll ever get them complete.
上尉，这里
Hauptsturmfürer, over here.
不，那些是我的东西
No, these are mine.
非常愿意送你回家 这样就不用你自己拿了
I'd be glad to take you home. So you don't have to carry them.
不用了 有人接我的，非常感谢
That's not necessary. I am being picked up. Thank you very much.
也许我们还会见面
Maybe I'll see you around.
希望如此 再见
I'd like that. Good bye.
- 你真会调情啊 - 是吗
You flirt very easy. Yes, well men…
- 他叫蒙茨，人还不错
Müntze, he's called. Quite a nice guy.
党卫队保安部的头目 抵抗组织很多人都死于他手
Chief of the SD. Because of him lots of people of the resistance have died.
那种人也会收集邮票？
And a man like that collects stamps?
如果战后他被送上刑场 我会很高兴说：开枪！
If he ever faces the wall after the war, I'll be glad to say: Fire.
- 小心 - 对不起
Watch out. - Sorry.
看，他找到一些
Look, he found something.
小心！
Watch it.
葛本先生，是我们的汽车
Mr. Gerben, it's our car.
不要碰那些！
Don't touch that.
- 弄开，快！ - 卡住了
Open up. OPEN. - It's jammed.
天啊
Jesus.
他们发现了武器！
They've seen the weapons.
快出来，跑！
Get out. Run.
嘿，站住！
Hey, stop there.
- 葛本 - 该死的
Gerben. - God damn.
葛本！
Gerben.
- 太晚了，他们会抓住你的 - 那是我儿子！
You're too late. They'll get you. - He's my son.
他们抓住你的话我们就都完了 你知道太多，他们会拷问出来的
If they get you, we're all fucked. You know too much: They'll beat it out of you.
凯普斯先生，我们无能为力
Mr. Kuipers, there's nothing more we can do.
把所有东西都带到赛伦提默 艾莉丝，你带上那些装空投物资的手提箱
Here, take everything to Silentium. Ellis, you take the suitcases of the dropping.
汉斯，给他们打电话 告诉他们我们这里已经暴露了
Here Hans, call them. Tell them there's a contamination here.
这要感谢那个叫蒙茨的混蛋 现在蒂姆被抓了
Thanks to that arse called Müntze, they now have Tim.
等下
Wait a minute.
请告诉他们汤馆现在关门了
Please tell'em the soup kitchen is now closed.
你在火车上遇到蒙茨的，对吧？
You met this Müntze in the train, right?
- 他有些喜欢你吧 - 那杂种喜欢上她了
And he kinda liked you. The bastard, adored her.
不要那么敏感
Oh don't overreact.
他给我看他的邮票 他正收集威廉敏娜的邮票
He showed me his stamps. He's collecting Wilhelmina.
你愿意和他接触到什么程度？
How far, would you be willing to go with him.
什么程度？
How far?
- 你是说跟他上床？ - 这样说太不雅了
You mean: Sleep with him? That's a rude way of saying it.
我希望说清楚 你是那个意思吧？
I like things to be clear. Is that what you mean?
你能做到什么程度？ 为了蒂姆，还有其他人
How far would you go? For Tim. For the others.
只要蒙茨愿意的话 我都做，可以不？
As far as Müntze is willing to go. OK?
真是罪恶 死人裹新装，活人穿旧衣
a deadly sin: A good suit for a dead body, while everyone else walks in rags.
- 顾客就是上帝 - 她把箱子放哪里了？
The customer remains king. Where did she put the suitcase?
那边，办公室里
Over there, in the office.
你考虑到了每个细节 都是为了那个混蛋德国佬
You think of everything. And that for that fucking kraut.
走开，不关你的事
Go away. This is none of you business.
- 火车上遇险后，也许可以有点… - 不，一点也不行
After the train incident, maybe a little? No, not even a little.
好吧，我是来拿手提箱的
Alright. I am here for the suitcase.
那儿
Over there.
该死的，都湿透了
Goddamn. It's soaking wet.
- 碎了？ - 希望没有，是胰岛素
It broke? - I hope not. It's insuline.
有些人必须要靠它 那些糖尿病人，如果没有胰岛素的话…
There's a dying need for that. Imagine a diabetic, without his insuline…
- 那他就得说再见了 - 告诉我详情
…he can say bye bye. - Tell me about it.
你也有糖尿病？ 我倒是没注意
You have it as well? I never noticed.
不，我很健康
No I don't. I am healthy.
别看了！
Stop watching.
剧团里有个患糖尿病的喜剧演员 每次演出前都要进行注射
At the revue, there was diabetic comedian. He always injected before a performance.
如果注射过多的话，他还得 吃一堆巧克力，真是受罪
Then he had to eat a lot of chocolate, if he injected too much. A never ending bother.
是啊，但总比痛苦死去要好
Yes, but still better than dying of pain.
这些英国货 至少一半都碎了
British bastards. At least half of it is broken.
医院可要高兴了
The hospital will be happy with that.
你要胰岛素干吗？
…………
不要问了 我也不会泄漏什么秘密
Don't ask, so I can't give away any secrets.
扎到了，医生 好痛，好痛
It stings, doctor. It stings, It stings, It stings,
要不要医生看一眼啊？
Shall the doctor have a look at it?
这样我还是第一个尝鲜啊
So I am still the first one.
进来
Yes?
威姆，那个女孩又来了 这回她看起来像是简·哈洛（女演员）
Wim, the girl is here again. This time she looks like Jean Harlow.
瑞秋，你回来了？
Rachel. You're back?
我们没能越过俾斯伯士河
We never got any further than the Biesbosch.
你的父母和马科斯… 他们和你一起的，不是吗？
And your parents and Max… They joined you didn't they?
我们突然遇到德国人的巡逻船…
Suddenly there was a patrol boat of the krauts and..
真不幸
Stupid coincedence
奇怪，他们都死了 我却哭不出来
Strange. Everybody's dead and I can't cry for them.
- 谁带你们过去的？ - 一个船长，我想他也死了
Who fared you over? - A skipper. Also dead, I think.
但总有人把你们带到 俾斯伯士河，对吗？
But someone brought you to the Biesbosch, right?
一个地下组织的人
A man from the underground.
是谁？
Who was that?
范·亨，我记得别人这么叫他
van Gein, he was called I think.
我深表同情
Disgusting. My sympathies.
我要去为女王和国家作些事
I am supposed to work for queen and country
去接近一个党卫队保卫部的高级官员
… by getting friendly with a high ranking SD- Officer.
甚至可能和他上床
maybe even sleep with him.
那你就要靠你自己了 无法帮助你
You're on your own with that. Can't help you with that.
不
No.
也许这里的某样东西可以帮到我
But maybe there's something in here, that can help me.
我是来见蒙茨上尉的
I am here to see captain Müntze
真的？什么事情？
really and why?
是关于皇宫的事 关于女王威廉敏娜本人
It's about the royal house. Queen Wilhelmina in person.
送她去蒙茨上尉那里
send her to captain Müntze
请稍坐一会，他马上就来
You are being expected. Wait over there.
弗里斯小姐
Ms. de Vries..
真是个惊喜 我肯定是交了什么好运气
What a surprise. To what do I owe the pleasure?
我在荷属印度群岛的 亲戚常常写信联系
I have family in the dutch Indies. They always wrote.
我母亲一直留着这些信 我就把邮票弄下来给你带来了
My mother kept the letters. I have softened the stamps off for you.
用水蒸汽弄下来的
with steam.
太棒了
Amazing.
漂亮，真漂亮
beautiful, very nice.
你好
Good day.
放那边吧，罗妮 我可不想弄脏了这些漂亮邮票
Put it over there, Ronnie. I don't want to damage these lovely stamps.
- 我帮你倒水吗？ - 不用了，我自己来吧
Shall I serve you? - No don't bother, I'll do that.
尝尝那些巧克力，英国的
Take some of the chocolate. British.
偶然弄到的
We got them by chance.
吃吧
Take some.
你这些邮票原来都留着干吗的
What were you planning to do with these stamps.
没什么啊，就是在我的抽屉里放着
Nothing special, they were in a drawer in my place.
差不多都是我所没有的 威廉敏娜邮票
Almost all the Wilhelmina stamps I don't have
如果你喜欢 就全部给你吧
If you see anything of interest, take it.
谢谢你 太感谢了
Thank you. I appreciate it.
进来
Yes.
关上门
close the door.
上尉，您的车准备好了
Captain, your car is ready.
已经好了？ 请帮我拿上帽子和大衣
Already? Take my hat and coat please.
真糟糕，要工作了 我还没来得及挑选呢
Too bad, duty calls. I haven't been able to choose yet.
那就都留在你这里吧
Then I'll leave them here.
谢谢
Thank you.
我觉得我吃了太多的巧克力 这不好吧？
I think I ate too much chocolate. Is that bad?
我不是每天都能吃到的
I don't get it everyday.
我要去参加一个聚会 那有更多好吃的
I have to go to a party. There will be much more to eat there.
你回家带上你的唱片和留声机 然后和我一起去，怎么样？
What if you could go home and pick up your phonograph and records and join me?
我来自己唱怎么样？
How about I sing?
那更好
Even better.
没有海牙的保安部 我们是不可能成功的
Without the SD from The Hague. All our successes had not been possible.
你们和恐怖分子的斗争 就是我们的斗争
Your fight against the terrorists is our fight.
我们将和元首一起 为一个自由的欧洲而战！
With the Fürer we fight for a free europe.
希特勒万岁
Heil Hitler.
开始奏乐，富兰肯
And now music. Franken.
＂旗帜飘扬 看我们队伍多雄壮＂
# die Fahne hoch die Reihen fest sind geschIossen
＂突击队前进 脚步坚定从容＂
# SA marschiert mit ruhig festem Schritt
＂倒在赤色分子枪口下的同志们＂
# Kam'raden, die Rotfront und Reaktion erschossen
＂你们的精神与我们同行 与队伍同行＂
# marschier'n im Geist in unser'n Reihen mit
＂倒在赤色分子枪口下的同志们＂
# Kam'raden, die Rotfront und Reaktion erschossen
＂你们的精神与我们同行 与队伍同行＂
# marschier'n im Geist in unser'n Reihen mit
弗里斯小姐？
Ms. de Vries?
你没事吧？
Everything OK?
香槟酒闹的
The champagne didn't go down well.
我现在是一点酒都不能沾
I am not used to any alcohol anymore.
但是，现在又好了
But, I'm alright now.
要不要我唱歌啊？
Shall I sing some?
将军，女士们，先生们
General, ladies and gentlemen…
很荣幸向你们介绍 艾莉丝·弗里斯
It is my great honour to present you Ellis de Vries.
她将给我们唱歌
She will sing some for us.
谁要点歌？
Any requests.
《罗拉》，《时髦的罗拉》
Lola. Die fesche Lola.
对，《罗拉》，《罗拉》
Yes, Lola, Lola
＂我是时髦的罗拉＂
# ich bin die fesche Lola
＂是最时髦的宠儿 有个自动钢琴机，就在我家大厅里＂
# der Liebling der Saison. ich hab'ein Pianola. zu Haus in mein'm Salon.
＂我就是时髦罗拉 没有男人不爱我＂
# ich bin die fesche Lola mich liebt ein jeder Mann
＂但我的自动钢琴机 谁也不许碰＂
# doch an mein Pianola da lass ich keinen 'ran
罗拉，罗拉
Lola, Lola
＂我是时髦的罗拉 是现在最时髦的宠儿＂
# ich bin die fesche Lola der Liebling der Saison
＂有个自动钢琴机，就在我家大厅里＂
Ich hab'ein Pianola. zu Haus in mein'm Salon.
＂如果谁想引开我 引我离开大厅＂
# und wer mich will begleiten da d'runten aus dem Saal
＂我就用拳捶他 再狠踢他一脚＂
# den hau ich auf der Saiten und treff'ihn aufs Pedal
罗拉！
Lola.
再见
bye
那么…
so?
什么？
so what?
我想看看你的邮票
I'd like to see your stamps.
邮票太多了
There's quite many of them.
我有的是时间
I have lots of time.
我可没有多余的牙刷
I don't have any toothbrush for you.
刷好了
brushed.
不错啊
Not bad.
从被我们赶出去的 资本家手里夺来的
from the capitalists, we kicked out.
掠夺是属于胜利者的
the loot is for the winners.
完全正确
exactly.
你唱得很好 原来你在哪里演出？
You sing well. Where did you sing.
在柏林 跟剧团在酒店表演
In Berlin. Cabaret, revue.
你真该继续唱下去
You should have continued.
现在没人需要那些了
There is no need for that anymore now.
你头发以前是黑色的
Your hair is normally black.
现在流行金发，不是么？
Blond is fashion now.
或许这能使你活下来 如果你是犹太人的话
Or this fashion, will help you survive, for instance if you are a jew.
对，那又怎么样呢？
So what?
这也是犹太族的？
Are these jewish?
这里也是金色的 你真是个完美主义者
Also blond. A perfectionist
- 哦，对不起 - 进来吧，都是女孩
Oh, sorry. Come on in. girls are allowed.
你做完爱后也要小便吗？ 今晚你唱得棒极了
Do you also have to pee, after sex? You were really great tonight.
蒙茨雇用你了吗？ 你是想找份工作，对吧？
Did he hire you, Müntze? You came looking for a job, right?
还没，我确实想找一个 但我不是国家社会主义党成员
No, but I am searching for one. But I am no party (NSB) member
我也不是 虽然我也支持他们
Neither am I, although I do agree with them.
荷兰毕竟是德国的一部分了
Holland is after all a piece of Germany.
大家都说类似德国方言
We all speak a sort of german dialect.
啊，真好，真的肥皂
Oh, nice: real soap.
还有丰盛的食物和饮料 你还能奢望更多吗？
And good food and great drinks. What more do you want?
罗妮？
(FRANKEN:) Ronnie?
只要保证，那些高级军官 永远都想要你
Make sure, a high ranked kraut never gets enough of you.
- 贡特尔，在这里 - 罗妮？
Günther. Over here. - Ronnie?
你们俩正在玩吗？
Are you playing with each other?
我们正在谈工作 艾莉丝想在我们这里做事
We were talking about work. Ellis would like to work for us.
德语歌唱得这么棒的人 可以马上被雇用
Someone who sings such good german is hired right away.
前提是…
That is if…
你得通过体检
you pass the inspection.
如果这还不健康 真不知道什么是了
If that isn't healthy, I don't know what is…
不，不，那是给蒙茨上尉的
NO, NO, these are reserved for captain Müntze.
- 你去哪儿了？ - 在厕所
Where were you? On the toilet.
富兰肯给了我一份工作
Franken offered me a job.
好主意，你可以明天开始 帮助筹备元首的生日
Good idea. You can start helping with the Fürer's birthday tomorrow.
我看到你结过婚了 有可爱的孩子
You're married, I see. Nice kids you have.
曾经是的
Was. I was married.
现在不是了？
Not anymore?
不，不再是了
NO, not anymore.
戈林曾发誓说
G鰄ring, had sworn…
英国不会向德国投炸弹
… that no english bomb would fall on Germany.
克莉斯蒂娜和我孩子们 躲在了错误的地方
Christina, was with the children in the wrong hideout.
我当时不在
And I wasn't there.
正中目标
bulls eye.
一无所有的感觉，艾莉丝 很痛苦
To not have anything, Ellis… Isn't much.
是啊，我明白
I know.
那声音对你来说一定好极了
For you it must be a beautiful sound.
嘘…
SShhh…
你什么也没告诉我们
You haven't told us anything.
我真的不知道 是别人把武器放到车上的
I don't know anything. Someone else put those weapons in the car.
你只是我们通向胜利 道路上微不足道的一小堆狗屎
You are just a little piece of shit on our road to final victory.
再过几周，俄国人就会把 你们丢入海里，连同你那些刽子手们
In a few weeks, the Russians will throw you in the sea, along with your executioners.
赏给你的
For you.
还有给你的斯大林
And for your comrad Stalin.
狗杂种
Dirty bastard.
真会说脏话
What a filthy language.
给他洗嘴
wash his mouth.
他在憋气
He's holding his breath.
抬起来
Up
不到一小时你就会讲了
Within the hour you'll talk.
- 就我们自己？ - 是啊，其他人都逃回德国了
Are we here alone? - The rest fled back to Germany.
你坐这里吧 这样我们可以挨近些
Could you come and sit here? So we can sit next to each other.
把它打出来 再复印15份
Type it out and copy it 15 times.
你的军装脏了
You have spots on your uniform.
没事，只是些水 快点，一会还有更多事要做
It's nothing, just water. Hurry up, there will be more to do.
你念，我打
If you read, I'll type.
得拿掉这些，不然我打不了字
Let's take these of, with them I can't type.
- 是真的吗？ - 当然了，你认为是什么啊？
Are these real? - Of course, what did you think?
从贡特尔那里拿的，漂亮吧 他的保险箱就是个宝库
Got it from Günther. Nice, huh? His safe is a real treasure hole.
- 芝麻开门 - 对，就是那样
Open Sesame. - Yes just like that.
还有满满一盒钻石
There's a whole box full of diamonds.
好了
Right.
1944年4月19日 好了，开始吧
Let's see: 1945, 19th. There we go.
艾莉丝？你可以念了
Ellis? You can start.
恐怖分子提姆图斯·凯普斯给出如下…
The terrorist Timotheus Kuipers gave the following…
你可以念的稍微快一些
You can speed up a little bit.
…供词
…statement.
我是抵抗组织的一员
I am a member of a resistance group.
我父亲，葛本·凯普斯 是这个组织的首领
My father, is head of the group: Gerben Kuipers.
很无聊，是吧？
boring, huh.
放开我！
-  Untranslated subtitle -
艾莉丝？
Ellis?
您在这里干吗？
What are you doing here?
和德国人交涉公正
To talk with the germans about justice.
公正？这里？
Justice, HERE?
抵抗组织的人没有人权 但我是律师，我尽力帮助他们
People of the resistance have no rights, but as a lawyer, I try to help them nonetheless.
和像富兰肯这种人商量？ 简直是浪费时间
With a guy like Franken? A waste of time.
蒂姆的窃听器
Tim's microphone.
你怎么知道我在这里？
How did you know I was here?
我不会低估你的
I do not underestimate you.
蒙茨是个不错的家伙 你不觉得么？
That Müntze guy, is quite nice, don't you think?
帮我一把，我们得去 装饰走廊，为元首的生日做准备
Could you give me a hand? We have to decorate the hallway for the Fürer's birthday.
您来了，斯马尔先生 进来
Mr. Smaal, you are here. Come in.
不对，钢琴应该摆在那里
No the pian should go there.
又来一些
Some more
- 谢谢你 - 再见
Thank you. - Good bye.
真漂亮
That looks great.
别忘了元首在右的规则
Don't forget to put the Fürer in the right perspective.
- 聚光灯给我照一下 - 上尉！
Give me a spotlight. - Captain.
这是对那3个恐怖分子的 死刑执行命令
the execution order for the 3 terrorists.
明天执行 请在这里签字
Tomorrow we shoot'em. just sign here.
绝对不行 谁也不许枪决
Absolutely not. No one is getting shot.
但他们都承认了 必须枪决他们
But they confessed, they have to be shot.
这是元首的命令，你知道的
Fürer's order, you know that.
但我是这里的负责人
Only I am in command here.
我说不许枪决 那你就不能枪决！
No executions, if I say so.
走吧
Dismissed.
希特勒万岁！
Heil Hitler.
天啊，连德国人自己也开始 争起来了，战争什么时候才结束啊
Jesus, if even those germans start to fight among each other, where will it end?
照向我，跟上
To me. Follow me!
艾莉丝？
Ellis?
- 艾莉丝？ - 我就来了
Ellis? - I'm coming
- 你在这里干吗？ - 让他高兴些
What are you doing here? - To cheer him up.
- 最漂亮的留给你 - 真好
The nicest one is for you. - That's sweet.
跟我一起回去吗？
Are you coming with me?
- 我得回家一趟 - 啊，那我今晚见不到你了？
Actually I have to go home. - So I won't be seeing you tonight?
当然能见到 我只是回家取些衣服
Of course you will. I just have to pick up some clothes.
喔，亲爱的…
Oh Honey..
我的小宠物
My little animal.
小宠物…喔…
animal…. ahh…
- 它起作用了 - 艾莉丝
It works. - Ellis.
- 罗妮，罗妮… - 快，快，要来了，来了
Ronnie, Ronnie… Yes, yes, cum, cum
- 老天，真是个可爱的小宠物 - 不就是个傍德国佬的脏妓女吗
Jesus, what a horny animal. - Just a dirty kraut whore.
- 我们会让她们偿还的 - 剔光她们，再蘸上沥青
We'll get those after the war. - Shave'm and then put their heads in tar.
- 然后杀了她们 - 行了，不要这么野蛮
and after that shoot'em. -  come on, don't be so primitive
我们不是为了那些而战
That's not what we fight for.
该死的电话！
Damn, that fucking phone.
不要停，继续啊
Don't stop, keep going.
我都快来了，你看你滴的
I almost came, watch it you're dripping.
富兰肯 好的，让他进来
Franken. Yes, send him in.
我们今晚继续，现在快离开这里
We'll continue tonight. And now go.
卡斯
Cas.
- 你好，最近怎样？ - 还不错
Good day, how are you? - fine.
坐吧，上次欠的钱还没给你呢
Sit down. I still owe you money from last time.
- 那是什么声音？ - 他正开他的保险箱
What's that? - He's opening his safe.
这有张新的单子给你 放桌子上了
There's a new list before you on your desk.
不是很多 还值那么多吗？
Not many. Is it still worth it?
至少弄个50万
Easily half a million.
这可能是最后一次出手了
I think this will be the last ride.
- 那个声音很耳熟 - 嘘…
I know that voice. - Sssshhh…
什么？
What?
- 那声音让我想起那个帮我们逃跑的人 - 不要说话
It reminds me of the man who helped us flea. - Shut up.
- 该死，发电机不正常了 - 我去修下
Shit, the generator is cutting out. - I'll fix it.
- 你可以点一下 - 不必了
You can count it. - Don't have to.
下次运送什么时候准备好？
When can you have the next transport to be ready?
他们住的都很近 也许3天吧
They live close together. Maybe 3 days?
就是他 那个范·亨
That's him. That's van Gein.
那些富裕的犹太人 都是来自同一个圈子的
Those rich jews always come from the same circles.
不关你的事
None of your business
如果我想的话 我可以找到你的线人
If I wanted to, I could find out who your informant is.
那会要了你的命
This could cost you your head.
也可能在战后救我的命
Or save mine after the war.
战后我就不会在这里了 来喝一杯吧
After the war, I won't be here. Come let's have a drink.
为下一批愚蠢的犹太人干杯
To the next load of stupid jews.
那次遇到德国巡逻船 不是什么巧合
So it wasn't a coincedence, that german boat.
是个陷阱 他们一直按着名单来
It was a trap. They're just working on a list.
什么名单？
What list?
有钱犹太人的名单，他们假装答应 带他们去比利时，却会路上杀掉你
Jews with money. They promise to take them to Belgium, but instead they kill them.
- 你怎么知道？ - 因为我也被算计过
How do you know? - Cuz I have been set up to.
因为我的全家都被他们屠杀了
Because I have seen my whole family being slaughtered.
天啊，艾莉丝… 真是太可怕了
Jesus, Ellis…. That's horrible.
- 范·亨是谁 - 他假扮是抵抗组织的人
Who is this van Gein? He poses as someone of the resistance.
他告诉犹太人说，可以帮他们逃跑 但确保带上钱财以维持生计
He tells jews, that they can run for it, just make sure to bring your money.
富兰肯就等着他们来 然后杀光他们，再掠夺钱财
Franken, waits for them, kills them and finally robs them.
因此现在又有新的 将要受害的名单来了
So now there's a new list of potential victims.
我们不能让他们得逞
We cannot let that happen.
可我们不知道名单里都是些谁 又都在哪里
We don't know who they are, or where they are.
- 如果我们直接杀了那个富兰肯呢？ - 嗯，干掉那个杂种
What if we just kill Franken? -  Yes, stop that bastard.
不，如果我们杀了他 他手里的二三十个俘虏就会被送上刑场
NO, if we kill him, 20- 30 hostages will line up against a wall.
如果我们不杀他 那就会有二三十个犹太人被杀
We don't shoot Franken and 20- 30 jews will be killed.
难道随便一个犹太人的生命 都比一个优秀的荷兰人要珍贵吗？
Is the life of a random jew, worth more than a good Dutchman?
谁决定的，你吗？
Who decides that, you?
不能干掉富兰肯
Franken, will not be liquidated.
范·亨，我们干掉他 一样可以阻止他们
Van Gein. We kill him and it ends as well..
不能杀人 斯马尔先生，你的意见呢
No killing. Mr. Smaal, your call.
为了葛本 我正在和德国人谈判休战的事
On behalf of Gerben, I am negotiating a truce.
如果我们不再发起攻击 那么蒙茨也保证不再报复，这样也许能行
We do no more attacks and Müntze promises not to retaliate. Might work.
啊，原来富兰肯和蒙茨吵架是因为这个
Ah, so that's why that fight happened between Franken and Müntze.
葛本，祝贺你 你救了你的蒂姆
Gerben, congratulations. You saved, your Tim.
是他和其他人！ 你有什么意见吗？
Him AND others. Is that a problem for you?
我？没问题 如果那些都是“好”的荷兰人的话
Me? No. If those are the 'good' Dutchman
够了，艾莉丝，葛本是领导 他说不行，那么这件事就此打住
That's enough, Ellis. Gerben is chief. If he says no, than it ends there.
再见
Good day to you.
艾莉丝
Ellis.
事情有时就是这样的 窃听器安装你干得真漂亮
Things are, the way they are. That microphone of yours, is absolutely brilliant.
艾莉丝
Ellis.
我赞成你，我们不能让 那些犹太人就这么被杀害
I agree, with you. We can't let those jews be slaughtered.
葛本也是对的 我们不能就这么杀掉那个范·亨
Gerben is also right. We can't just kill van Gein.
如果他只是消失了呢？
What if he just dissapears?
富兰肯会知道的 他会枪决我们的人
Franken, will know. He will have people shot.
也许他以为范·亨逃跑了
Or he thinks, van Gein has deserted.
可他们刚商量好新的名单
After he just promised him a new list?
考虑到战后，范·亨努力躲起来了 就像他自己那么说的
Van Gein, is trying to cover up, for after the war, says so himself.
如果他消失了 富兰肯会认为他只是跑了
If he disappears, Franken will think, he just ran.
凯普斯和斯马尔忽略了一件事
There's one thing, Kuipers and Smaal pass by too easy.
某个人已经从事陷害 犹太人的勾当很久了
Someone has been setting up jews for a long time.
范·亨知道那个嫌疑人 他必须告诉我们
van Gein has a suspect. He'll have to tell us.
不得已的话我会拷问他说出来 来，我去召集我的手下
If I have to I'll beat it out of him. Come. I'll round up my boys.
我不能去，我还得去见蒙茨
I can't. I'm meeting Müntze.
只有你知道范·亨的样子 没你帮助我们找不到他的
You alone, know van Gein's face. We can't do anything, without you,
你必须得来
- You must be in.
就是他
That's him.
行动
Let's go.
把你围巾给我
Give me your shawl.
动手
Now.
他没子弹了
It's empty.
提欧
Theo.
- 开枪，开枪！ - 我下不了手
Shoot. Shoot. - I can't.
- 开枪啊！ - 我不能…
Shot. - I can't
啊，该死的！
Aaahhh.. Goddamn.
婊子，该死的婊子！ 我要你死…
Bitch. Goddamn bitch. I will goddamn….
你诅咒别人
You curse.
亵渎者
Blasphemer.
你咒骂别人！
You curse.
够了，提欧 提欧，来！走了！
That's enough, Theo. Theo, come!
啊…小心些
Aarrgghh… Be careful man.
皮肉伤，基斯 你算幸运的
Flesh wound, Kees. You got lucky.
但还是要把子弹取出来 艾莉丝，把氯仿拿来
The bullit must come out though. Ellis, take the chlorophorm.
深呼吸，基斯，深呼吸
Breathe deeply, Kees.
对，就是这样
Yes, like that.
住手！住手！
Stop it!
天啊，那鸟东西不管用 你这笨蛋！
Oh God, that shit doesn't work, you dick!
使用期限1941年 天啊，这东西早过期了
Expriry date 1941. Jessus, that stuff is way over due.
- 难怪范·亨才没被放倒 - 德国佬有什么东西能保质5年？
That's why van Gein wasn't knocked out. - What's still good after 5 years of krauts?
你想挨一锤子 还是喝口酒咬紧牙齿呢？
Choice: Hit by the hammer, or some booze and bite your teeth.
酒，笨蛋
Booze, dick.
- 干杯 - 干杯
Cheers. - Cheers.
基斯，想想快乐的事情
Kees, think of something nice.
好
OK
取出来了
Gotcha.
谢谢，笨蛋
Thanks, dick.
伙计们，合作愉快
Guys, cheers on a happy ending.
范·亨给德国佬提供了许多财宝
van Gein delivered the krauts tons.
许多？你是说几百万吧
Tons? You mean millions.
给，提欧
Come on Theo.
那些该死的荷兰人！ 他们杀了我最好的战士
Damn those dutchmen. They killed my best soldier.
这位勇敢的战友 带给了我上百万的财富
That brave warrior and comrad, handed me millions.
现在他死了 被那些该死的恐怖分子枪杀了
And now he's dead, shot by god damn terrorists.
我杀了人，我是坏人！
I shot a man. I am bad.
提欧，那是正义的 他才是杀人犯，不是你
That was justice. He's a murderer, you are not.
不，我是的 我和纳粹一样的坏
Yes I am. I am just as bad as the nazi's.
我说过不许这么做，不是吗？ 难道我没有说过吗？
I said no, didn't I? I said god damn No, didn't I?
那混蛋必须死 而且，这又有什么关系呢？
The bastard had to die. Besides, what does it matter?
这样蒂姆就会被枪决，你这笨蛋！
That Tim, will face the firing squad. Dick.
还有其他40个俘虏……
Along with 40 other hostages.
都因为你这个杀死范·亨的 抵抗组织“英雄”而送命
Because you as a resistance hero, had to go and shoot van Gein.
天啊，葛本，40个？ 你怎么知道的？
Jesus, Gerben. 40? How do you know?
从富兰肯那儿的窃听器里听到的
From the microphone we placed on Franken.
他的摇钱树被杀死了 他要报复
His best man killed. He wants blood.
你还在和蒙茨谈判吗？
You still negotiate with Müntze?
自从你这次行动后就没了
Not after the attack you pulled.
蒂姆没救了
Tim is as good as dead.
但你们犹太人却得救了
But your jews are saved…
艾莉丝，不要这样 都是我的错，不关其他人的事
Ellis, no. I am responsible. No one else.
我去自首 只有我才应该被枪决
I am turning myself in. Only I shall face the firing squad.
我跟你去，汉斯 我的罪孽最重
I will be beside you, Hans. I carry most of the guilt.
- 我也去 - 那我们都去
I will join too. -  Then we all go.
站住！真是荒谬 你们都喝醉了！
Stop it, this is ridiculous. You're all drunk.
不能让酒毁了我们的抵抗组织
Before you know it, all of the resistance will give up, because of gin.
自首不是解决问题的办法
Turning in, is not a solution.
那还能怎么办呢？
Then what is?
救出他们
Rescue them.
你不可能活着从 党卫队保安部的地下室出来的
You will not get out alive of the SD basement.
这是保安部办公室的建筑图纸 那里以前曾是银行
The building plans of the SD office, when it was still a bank.
从一个朋友那里拿到的
Got it from a friend
我来了
Here I am.
我以为你不来了呢
I thought: she's not coming back.
回家后就忘了时间了
I lost track of time at home.
然后又碰到宵禁 我只能偷偷溜来了
And then it was curfew and I had to sneak my way in.
那是什么东东啊？
What do we have here?
你以为我是傻子吗？
How dumb do you think I am?
突然间一个漂亮女人 闯进我的生活
Suddenly a beautiful woman comes into my life.
之后她又找到我的指挥部……
Later she comes to my headquarters…
她正巧有我要找的邮票
Then she accidentally has the stamps I am looking for.
又偶然发现她是犹太人
Then she coincidentally appears to be jewish.
而且刚来这里工作不久
And as soon as she comes to work here..
富兰肯最好的间谍就被杀了
Franken's best undercover man, gets killed.
太巧合了 你不认为吗？
Quite a coincedence don't you think?
自己选择，要么沉默 那么我明天就把你交给富兰肯
Choice: be silent and I will hand you to Franken tomorrow.
要么你告诉我所有的事
Or you tell me everything now
除非你把枪拿开……
Only if you put away that gun…
并吻我
… and kiss me now.
我吻你了
I kissed you.
现在告诉我
Now tell me.
女士们，脱掉外衣 开始工作
Put away your jackets and get to work.
给所有的监狱打电话
Call all prisons and ask..
问一下他们共有多少俘虏
How many hostages they have…
满40个就可以了 今天押送
You can stop at 40 pieces, Delivery today.
枪决将在明早6点钟执行
Executions, will be tomorrow morning at 06:00
女士们，不用打电话了
Those calls will not be necessary.
中尉，打开你的保险柜
Lieutenant, open your safe.
当然，您要找哪个文件？
Of course. What document are you looking for?
不是，你涉嫌抢劫谋杀犹太富人
None, you are under the suspicion of robbing and killing rich jews.
我们并不反对这样…
There's nothing against that…
但是你被控告 私自占有犹太人的财产
…but you are accused of keeping their treasure to yourself.
对于不上交犹太人财产 给帝国的人
By not handing over jewish property to the empire…
将被送上军事法庭审判 可能被判死刑，打开你的保险柜
… you risk court martial and the death penalty. Open your safe.
遵命，将军
At your order, general.
清空，快
Empty it quickly.
这里呢？
And here?
请打开
Open it please.
从39年起 我们战役开始的那一年
From '39, when we started our campaign
我一直存着 等到我们胜利那天
Saved it for our victory.
看起来你的人消息有误啊
Your Informant seems to have been mistaken.
这个人一向消息很灵通的
This person is always well informed.
这次可不是
Not this time.
很抱歉，富兰肯
My apologies, Franken.
我们的讨论还没结束
This is not the end of this discussion.
将军…
- General…
蒙茨在与恐怖分子谈判
Müntze is negotiating with terrorists.
他答应他们不予以还击
He promised them, no more retaliation.
甚至对范·亨被谋杀也不还击
Even not for the murder of van Gein.
你和恐怖分子谈判？
You negotiate? With terrorists?
如果我们停止追究
The resistance is willing to stop and give in their weapons.
抵抗组织愿意停止战斗 并交出他们的武器
If we stop retaliating.
这有背于元首9月4号的命令 命令必须无条件执行！
This is in violation of a Fürer order of the 4th of September.
为什么要留更多的血呢，将军？
Which stays in force! - Why shed more blood?
俄国人已经到了柏林 那香槟恐怕永远也喝不到了
Russians in Berlin. That Champagne will never be drunk.
这是失败主义言论，上尉
That is defeatism.
和敌人谈判更是叛国罪
And negotiating with enemy is high treason.
警察，逮捕这个人
Police, arrest this man.
这意味着死刑，蒙茨
This means death penalty, Müntze.
我会亲自指挥你的枪决
And I will lead the firing squad.
准备好了
Ready.
汉斯，这是进去的通行证
Hans, the papers to get inside.
钥匙呢？
And the keys?
复制的 从承包商祖特菲纳那里搞到的
Duplicates. From contractor Zutfenaar.
就是那个建监狱的人
Who build the cells.
我让他自己选择 是想吃子弹，还是战后拿勋章
I let him choose: A bullet now, or a medal after the war.
他就很乐意地给我了
He gave'm gladly.
葛本，你要干什么？
Gerben, what are you up to?
我不会让你们单独去的
I will not let you go alone.
- 这事我决定，你留在这里 - 我不能干坐着
I decide that. You stay here. - I can't stay here and do nothing.
我会救出那40个战友 你的任务是带他们安全离开这里
I'm going to liberate 40 man. It's your job to get them safely out of here.
每个人都有自己的任务 钥匙给我
Everybody has a job, that one is yours. The keys.
葛本
Gerben.
蒂姆一定会回来的 我向你承诺
You will get Tim back. On my word of honour.
- 你怎么还不就位？ - 蒙茨被捕了
Why aren't you at your station? Müntze go arrested.
- 我们听说了 - 很好，德国佬自相残杀了
Yes we heard. - Good so the krauts are killing among themselves.
- 救出蒙茨 - 想也别想
Get Müntze out. - Over my dead body.
救出蒙茨 不然我就退出
Get Müntze out, or I'm out.
你真让我们为难
That leaves us no choice.
- 你真的这么看重那个混蛋？ - 是的
You really think this highly of this dick? - Yes, I do.
好吧，带上他
Good. Take him.
- 嗨 - 嗨
Hi. - Hey
又是聚会，太好了
Nice, a party.
蒙茨被捕你一点也不担心？
Müntze being arrested doesn't do you anything?
只要活着，就有希望
Where there is life, there is hope.
我们还能有什么希望？
What hope, do we have left?
英国兵就要来了
That the Tommy's will arrive.
艾莉丝，我们完蛋了 我们给德国佬工作
Ellis, we're finished. We worked for the krauts.
被富兰肯折磨过的那些人的家属 会来这里找我们算帐
The families of the poor bastards that Franken tortured will come here.
抵抗组织的人也可能杀我们
Or the resistance will kill us.
他们不会杀任何人
The resistance won't kill anyone.
好像你知道似的
Like you know.
对，我知道
Yes, I do.
你认识那些家伙？
So you know those guys?
艾莉丝…你是？
Ellis…. What?
你是个间谍
You're a spy.
天啊 我从没想到你竟然会是间谍
Jesus. I had never thought you would.
就像演玛塔·哈里的那个葛丽泰·嘉宝 （玛塔·哈里：一战时荷兰的女间谍）
That's like Mata Hari, with Greta Garbo
女士们，大家在等你们
Ladies, you are expected.
你先去吧，我就来
You go ahead, I'll join.
那个嘉宝 最后还是死了
That Garbo, huh. She did die though.
请出示证件
Show me your papers.
从乌得勒支押来的俘虏
Hostages and terrorists from Utrecht.
一共6个人，明天枪决
6 men, for the execution tomorrow.
俘虏
Hostages.
可以了
Right.
进去吧
Move along.
开门
Open up.
你把车调个头
You turn the van around.
跟我来
Follow me.
胡斯
Guus.
艾莉丝
Ellis.
＂这就是我要唱得旋律＂
# ja, das ist meine Melodie nach der ich singen muss
＂口哨，舞动和跳动的旋律＂
# nach der ich pfeifen muss und tanzen muss, und springen muss
＂每个音符都会抓住你的心 每个人都为此陶醉＂
# die man beim ersten Ton versteht weil sie jedem in die Beine geht
＂就是这个旋律 让我感到幸福无比＂
# ja, das ist eine Melodie die mich so selig macht
＂当我听到这旋律 总是幸福不已＂
# wenn ich sie h鰎e, hab ich immer an das GI點k gedacht
＂请告诉我 你们也喜欢，我最爱的旋律＂
# ach bitte sagt mir, liebt ihr sie meine kleine Lieblingsmelodie
上
Go.
- 蒙茨也带走？ - 我们答应过艾莉丝
Müntze too? - We promised Ellis.
希姆
Siem.
嗨，我们来了
hi, come.
是我，玛登
It's me, Maarten.
玛登
Maarten.
嗨，蒂姆 伙计
Hi Tim, old boy.
大家一起唱
All together. Chorus.
伙计们，赶快
Boys hurry up.
下面发生什么事情了？
What's going on down there?
都在掌握之中
Nothing we can't handle.
卫兵
Guards.
蒂姆！
Tim.
- 快走 - 约普！
Go. - Joop.
- 怎么回事？ - 马上离开
What happened? - Go, now.
放松
Easy.
撞开它
Hit it.
罗妮，你去帮凯特纳先生 艾莉丝，你跟我来写份报告
Ronnie, you help K鋟tner. Ellis, come with me to write a report.
怎么样？
And?
那是个陷阱 我们完全失败了
A trap. Complete failure.
蒂姆他？
And Tim?
天啊…
oh God.
请坐吧
Have a seat.
艾莉丝，这事你办得真棒
Ellis you did a great job.
我非常满意
I am very satisfied.
应该的 每个人都该为元首尽忠
Well of course, one does what one can for the Fürer.
是啊，但结果真是 出乎意料的好
Yes, but the result is above all expectations.
- 这不可能 - 该死的！
It can't be true? - God damn
他们完全陷入了我们的圈套
They have been beautifully set up with that coal hatch.
就像瓮中之鳖
Like rats in cage.
这是你应得的钱
You earned your money fair and square.
那婊子出卖了我们 肮脏的犹太骗子！
The bitch tricked us. What a dirty jewish trick.
- 看到没，你绝对不能相信他们 - 安静！
See, you can't trust them. - Silence.
现在希姆莱的画像可以拿下来了 你可以亲自去拿，宝贝 （海因里希·希姆莱——党卫队首领）
Himmler can come down now. You may do that dear.
我们不再需要 这个英国玩具了
We won't be needing this english toy now anymore.
我亲爱的凯普斯先生 向您道别了
My dear Kuipers, Lieutenant Kuipers, is saying goodbye to you now.
艾莉丝，你还要说什么吗？
Ellis, one last word?
这婊子居然在笑
She laughs. That bitch laughs.
那么晚安，你做得很好 谢谢你的合作
Good night and good watch. Thank you for your cooperation.
您真是颇费周折，亲爱的
Never bite more than you can chew, darling.
明天你就会被送上刑场 和你的蒙茨一起
Tomorrow, firing squad, along side with your Müntze.
只要我还活着 我就要她死！
Even if it's the last thing I can do: That girl dies.
作为犹太人 她怎么能这样？
How can she do that, as a jew?
- 谁知道她承受了多少压力 - 即使这样…
Who knows, under how much pressure she was. - Still..
如果那是你 你选择子弹还是背叛呢
What if you had to chose between a bullet or treason.
这不是借口 无论如何，我们都要杀了她
An explanation is not an excuse. We kill the girl, no matter what.
无论如何！无论如何！
Wherever, whenever.
快走！
Move along.
空了！空了！
Empty, empty.
来，这儿
Here, come here.
不要啊，我的漂亮衣服 快，给我手帕
Oh, no my beautiful dress. Quickly a hanky.
好痒
That tickles.
嘘…
Ssshhh…
来
Come.
把枪给我
Give me the gun.
富兰肯永远也别想活抓我们 永远别想！
Franken, will never catch us alive. Never.
走吧
Move along
过来，快点
Come, hurry up.
都正常了吧，希格弗里德？
Everything in order again, Siegfried?
是啊
Yeah
走吧
Move along.
- 快走！ - 今晚你可真不友好啊
Make way! - Not very friendly today are we.
没想到你这么勤劳啊
Very diligent. I'd never have thought.
懒人，擦干
Here you lazy, dry'em.
很安逸吧
Cosy, huh?
我希望永远能这样
I wish, it could stay like that forever.
当然能 只要我们在一起
It can, if we stay together.
永远？
Forever.
但不能待在荷兰
But not here in Holland.
他们认为我是叛徒 会追捕我
They'll think I am a traitor. They will look for me.
我们必须澄清那事 把叛变的事实告诉他们
We'll have to straighten that out. We know what the treason was like.
你真乐观，你真以为他们会 听一个党卫队保安部军官说话吗？
Optimist. Do you really think they'll let you finish your talk as an SD- officer.
我们别无选择
We have no other choice.
［节目暂停，插播如下公告］
We interrupt this program for the following announcement:
［德国司令部同意撤出…］
The german command has agreed to surrender…
［…在荷兰以及德国西北 和丹麦的德军武装力量］
… Of all german armed forces in Holland, the north west of Germany and Denmark…
［全部交由第21军总司令接管］
To the commander in chief of the 21st army.
战争结束了，亲爱的 战争结束了
The war is over, my love. The war is gone.
［包括所有海军舰船］
This includes all the marine vessels.
对我们来说 只是刚刚开始
For us it is merely starting.
我从没想到过 我居然会害怕解放
I'd never thought to be afraid of liberation.
富兰肯中尉
Lieutenant Franken.
中尉
Lieutenant
解开绳索
Ropes away.
- 你设定好航向了吗？ - 是的
Did you set course? - Yes.
- 6小时后我们就在汉堡了 - 很好
In 6 hours, we'll be in Hamburg. - Very good
- 去下面检查一下 - 是
-  Have a look down below. -  Yes
约瑟夫，怎么回事？
Joseph, what's wrong.
约瑟夫？
Joseph?
你真以为我们会放过你吗？
Did your really think, we'd let you get away?
- 你怎么在这里？ - 来取你的命和你的财宝
What are you doing here? - You. And your treasure.
艾莉丝！
Ellis.
艾莉丝，这里 吉普车上
Ellis. Here, on the jeep.
- 罗妮 - 嗨，艾莉丝，加入我们
Ronnie. - Hi, Ellis. Join us.
- 你怎么到这上来了？ - 因为我站在前排
How did you get here? - Just stand in front.
欢声笑语，拥挤不堪
A bit of laughing and pushing around.
看，我的新男友 他拥有女孩想要的一切
Look, my new boyfriend. He has everything a girl wants.
尼龙布，巧克力，还有威士忌 我爱他！
Nylons, Chocolate and whiskey. Oh, I love him.!
- 上来吧 - 不了，我还有事
Come ride with me. No, I have no time.
好吧，再见
Ok, see you soon.
拜拜！拜拜！
Bye. Bye.
［卖国贼］
[Traitor]
［娼妓］
[Whore]
等一下 我们就来了
One moment, we're coming.
威姆，那些加拿大人来了
Come, Wim. The canadians are here.
不会吧，你们还都活着？
No. You're still alive?
是啊，惊讶吧 这么多人都想杀我们
Yes, strange huh, with all those people trying to kill us.
我以为富兰肯已经枪决了你们
I thought Franken had shot you.
他没告诉你我们逃走了？
Surely he told you we got away?
富兰肯？告诉我？
Franken? Tell me? Me?
我们已经出去躲了好几周了 才刚回来半小时
We've been in hiding for weeks. We just got home half an hour ago.
- 没人说你们要离开 - 你这是什么意思？
Who says you are not trying to leave? - What do you mean child?
加拿大战地保卫正要来接我们
I am about to be picked up by canadian field security
好，那我们跟你们一起去
Good, then we'll join you.
- 那我们在你办公室等吧 - 路德维希，你这是干什么？
We'll wait in your office. - Ludwig, what's wrong with you?
进去！
Go inside!
坐下
Sit down.
你们认为 我是那次伏击的幕后黑手吗？
So you think I am guilty for the desastrous attack?
是的 还有你对你犹太客户的屠杀
Yes and for the extradiction of your jewish clients.
你胡说！ 他们都是认识他多年的朋友
How dare you. Most of them knew him for years. They were friends.
我这么做有何利益？
What would be my gain?
为了偷走他们委托你的财宝 你和富兰肯！
By stealing of what they entrusted you with. You and Franken.
你告诉了他窃听器的事情
You betrayed him where the microphone was.
劫狱是你的主意
The hold up was your idea.
你设计想杀害汉斯和他的战友
You let Hans and his men get slaughtered.
等一下，等一下
Wait a minute, wait a minute.
又不是只有我知道这事 凯普斯也知道啊
I wasn't the only one. Kuipers knew all this as well.
但是没人会让自己儿子去死
But nobody will have his own son killed
每个人都有别人不知的秘密
Every man has unknown deapths.
我能给你们看些东西吗？
May I show you something?
我们躲起来后 我夫人和我努力回想过
While we were in hiding. My wife and I tried to put things in perspective.
我检查了我的记事本
I examined my agenda.
最后我们得出了一个基本结论 对吧，亲爱的？
And we came to a radical conclusion. Didn't we darling?
什么结论？
And that is?
你们得和我们一起去 加拿大警察那里
You'll have to join us by going to the canadian police.
现在就告诉我
Just tell me.
作为一个律师，我不能
As a lawyer, I can't.
我必须要保证公平性
I have to keep you unprejudiced.
一定是加拿大人来了
That will be the canadians.
每个嫌疑人都会 受到公正的审判
Every suspect deserves a fair trial.
即使是最毒辣的混蛋？
Even the biggest bastard?
也会如此
Even those.
我们来了 你？
We're coming. You?
威姆？
Wim?
待在这里
Stay here.
- 看 - 该死的，那是蒙茨，抓住他！
Look. - God damn, that's Müntze. Get him.
蒙茨，我们抓到蒙茨了！
Müntze, we've got Müntze.
我们抓到蒙茨了！
We have Müntze.
该死，那是艾莉丝·弗里斯 跟我来！
God damn. There's Ellis de Vries. Come with me.
艾莉丝·弗里斯
Ellis de Vries.
这里！
Over here.
抓到你了，婊子！
I've got you. Bitch.
蒙茨上尉 拿掉他的手铐，约翰
Captain Müntze. Take of his cuffs, John.
请坐
Please sit down.
这份报告上记载了关于…
In this report a collaboration is being described between…
…蒙茨和叫凯普斯的先生合作的事情
…Müntze and a certain Mr. Kuipers.
他怎么会参与进来，上校？
Why is this man gettin involved Colonel?
凯特纳将军友好地提供帮助 帮我们弄清这些乱事
General K鋟tner has very kindly offered to clear up this mess.
- 凯培斯是谁？ - 一个彻底的斯大林主义者
Who is this Kuipers. - A Stalinist in heart and soul.
他和蒙茨这几个月一直在共谋
He and Müntze haven been conspiring in the last few months.
只是想避免流血冲突！
To avoid bloodshed.
他在和共产主义者谈判 上校，那是我们未来的敌人
He was negotiating with the communists, Colonel, our future enemy.
你永远也搞不懂，凯特纳
You've got never K鋟tner.
我认为蒙茨为了保命 会不顾一切的撒谎
I consider Müntze a liar, who will do anything to save his own skin.
当然，谁不是呢？
Of course, who wouldn't?
无论如何，我们会查出真相的 约翰，带他去牢房
We'll get to the bottom of this. Take him to his cell.
如果你允许的话…
If you allow me.
约翰，等下
John.
这是死刑执行令
This is a death warrant.
蒙茨因为叛国罪 被军事法庭判处死刑
Müntze has been sentenced to death for high treason.
德国法律裁决和我无关 那些裁决都是无效的
The rulings of german law are none of my concern. Therefore the rulings are null and void.
不好意思，您肯定弄错了 英国军事法律是承认……
You have been misinformed. British military law does recognise the jurisdiction
…德国军事法庭的战地司法权的
…of german tribunals in the field
即使有条件投降后也是有效的
Even after capitulation.
具体请参见第153条
In article 153, to be exact.
你是建议我们枪决一个证人？
Are you suggesting we shoot a witness?
你们的将军福克斯 已经准许我们…
Your own general Foulkes has allowed us…
惩戒我们自己的军人
… to discipline our own men.
您可以打电话问他
You can call him and ask.
如果您拒绝执行蒙茨的判决 我将向福克斯将军提出控告
If you refuse to carry out a Müntze's sentence I will file a complaint with general Foulkes.
您肯定将后悔莫及
Which you will no doubt regret.
你知道将军是什么样的人
You know what generals are like.
宪兵！
MP.
把他带出去！
Get him out of here.
立正！
Attention.
瞄准！
Aim.
开枪！
Fire.
起来！去教堂做礼拜
Get up, you're going to church.
快点，带上你们的粪桶
Come on, bring your shit buckets.
- 跟上！ - 教堂在楼上
Go on, move. - Church is up stairs.
跟上！
Come on.
嘿，婊子 屎倒在那里
Hey bitch, shit is over there.
跟上！ 你把它拉上去，快点
Move along. You pull it up. Hurry up.
听听上帝的声音 也许会改变你们的命运
Listen ot the voice of God. Maybe you can change your ways.
向前看
Look ahead.
嘿，安静
Hey, silence.
安静！
silence.
我们是来看那帮卖国贼的 头抬起来，让我看看你们的脸
We come to see traitors. Heads up, let me see your faces.
- 看看他们 - 恶臭的脑袋
Look at them. - Dirty rotten heads.
- 也许其它部位还可以 - 脱掉你们的衣服！
Maybe the rest has some to offer. - Take of your clothes.
- 男的脱掉内裤 - 露出屁股！
Guys take off your pants. - Bare ass.
女的脱光上衣 我要看胸部！
All women naked on top. I wann see some tits.
这个也脱掉
This too.
脱掉！
Take it off
她给德国佬唱过歌
She sang for the krauts.
她也得给我们唱
She'll certainly sing for us.
- 给你唱？休想！ - 必须唱，每个人都要唱
Sing for you? Never. -  Of course you do. Everybody sings.
唱！
Sing.
想让我下不来台？
Do you want me to lose face?
没门，你这肮脏的德国婊子 臭妓女！
No way. Dirty Kraut bitch. Dirty whore.
揍她，揍她！
Hit her. Hit her.
闪开，躲开那婊子
Take cover, move away from the girl.
臭死了
Damn, it stinks.
谁有香水？
Who's got some perfume?
臭荡妇 肮脏恶臭的荡妇
Stinky slut. Dirty stinky slut.
消防员来了，躲开
Make way for the fireman.
别碰我的水管！
Stay away from my hose.
- 卷好 - 这里没士兵的事
Roll it up. - Soldiers have nothing to say down here.
这里我说了算
I am the boss here.
我是指挥官阿克曼斯 王子参谋处的
I am commander Akkermans. of the Prince's staff
这是令人唾弃的丑恶行径
This is a godforesaken scandal
令人耻辱！ 你们和纳粹没有两样
This is a disgrace. You're just as bad as the nazi's.
24小时内 你们都会被调离
Within 24 hours, you are out.
- 翻译给他们听，阿克曼斯 - 是，长官
Translate, commander Akkermans. - Yes, sir.
肮脏的法西斯分子 限你们24小时内离开
Dirty fascists, you'll be out of here within 24 hours.
上面的流氓 都给我滚出去！
And those punks up there, get out of here, now!
- 照看一下这可怜的姑娘 - 是，长官
See to this poor girl. - Sir.
艾莉丝，没事了，起来吧 没事了，起来
Ellis it's over. Come. It's over. Come.
我要离开这里
I want to leave.
来吧，亲爱的 都结束了
Come honey. It's over.
请稍等，弗里斯小姐 你的东西
Just a moment, Mrs. de Vries. Your personal belongings.
你能检查一下吗？
Could you check?
斯马尔的？
van Smaal?
阿克曼斯医生来了 是阿克曼斯医生
There goes the doctor. That's doctor Akkermans.
他曾在抵抗组织工作 阿克曼斯医生万岁！
He was in the resistance. Long live the doctor.
巧克力！巧克力！
Chocolate. Chocolate.
这儿，别都给了 供给还是很紧张的
Here, don't spend it all. Supplies are still scarce.
＂格林奇万岁，女王万岁＂
# oranje boven, oranje boven leve de koningin
我给你看些东西
I want to show you something.
- 你从哪里弄到这些的？ - 富兰肯试图带着这些逃跑
How did you get it? - Franken tried to get away with it.
都是他从被杀害的 犹太人身上偷的
Everything he robbed from the murdered jews.
这是我爸爸给我的 作为我第一次演出的奖励
I got this from my father, for my first performance.
那个杂种富兰肯陷害你，是吧？
That bastard Franken, tried to make you an accomplice, huh?
我会和凯普斯谈的 或者直接向王子讲
I'll talk to Kuipers about that. Or higher up with the Prince.
我会解释的
I'll explain.
他们不会相信你的
They'll never believe you.
都会好起来的，美好的结局 喝一杯？
Everything will be alright. A happy end. A drink?
还有件事，蒙茨被抓了 我想见见他
One more thing. Müntze got caught. I want to see him.
- 你还没听说吗？ - 什么？
Haven't you heard? - What?
- 这说起来太荒谬了 - 发生什么事了？
It's too insane for words. - What happened?
一个加拿大混蛋批准了…
A canadian dick allowed…
…德国佬执行蒙茨的死刑判决
…that the krauts could finish the death sentence.
到底何时才是个头？
Doesn't it ever stop?
艾莉丝？
Ellis?
这会让你平静下来
This will calm you down.
来，躺下
Come, lie down.
好些了吗？
Feeling better?
＂医生，医生…＂
Doctor, Doctor…
胰岛素，很多的胰岛素
Insuline. Too much insuline.
它会让你一睡不醒 永别了
That will put you to sleep. Forever.
＂阿卡曼斯医生，阿卡曼斯医生…＂
Doctor Akkermans. Doctor Akkermans.
他们的英雄得出场了
The 'hero' hast to show himself.
躺在这儿吧 很快你就能见到你家人了
Stay there. Soon you'll see your family again.
说不定还能见到蒙茨呢
and who knows, maybe Müntze too.
＂医生，医生…＂
Doctor, Doctor…
（荷兰国歌）＂拿骚的威廉姆斯 自古德意志血统＂
(Anthem:)# Wilhelmus van Nassouwe ben ik van Duitsen bloed
＂永远尽忠于祖国＂
# den vaderland getrouwe
＂至死也不会改变＂
# blijf ik tot in den dood
＂我乃奥林奇王子＂
# een prinse van Oranje
＂永远自由而无畏＂
# ben ik vrij onverveerd.
＂对于西班牙的王＂
# de koning van Hispanje
＂敬意忠诚永不减＂
# heb ik aItijd ge雃rd
拦住她！
Stop her.
她是病人，她病了 拦住她！拦住她！
She's a patient, she's ill. Stop her.
艾莉丝，艾莉丝！
Ellis. Ellis.
让开
Out of my way.
拦住她，她很危险
Stop her. She's dangerous.
放开我！
Let me go.
拦住她，她很危险
Stop her. She's dangerous.
放开我 该死的，放开我！
Let me go. Goddamnit, let me go.
我会抓住你的，婊子
I'll get you, you whore.
放开我，混蛋 放开我！
Let me go, bastards, let me go!
金戒指，编号23
Golden ring, number 23
我们找到他了
We found him.
葛本，我想你最好走开下
Gerben, I think you'd better go.
可以让我们自己的人做吗？ 我不想让德国佬碰他
Can our own people do this? I don't want the krauts to touch him.
你们住手
You, stop.
伙计们，你们接手 为了葛本
Guys take over, it's for Gerben.
凯培斯先生，一位女士想和你谈谈 艾莉丝·弗里斯
Mr. Kuipers? A lady wants to speak to you. Ellis de Vries?
等一下，凯培斯先生 请冷静，凯培斯先生！
Wait Mr Kuipers. Calm down please, Mr Kuipers.
她有这些死人的消息和名字
She has information, names.
包括你儿子
About these dead people, including your son.
您想听她说说吗？
Will you listen to her?
好吧
Yes.
艾莉丝！
Ellis?
你知道这是谁吗？
Do you know, who this is?
- 你还有什么要说的？ - 这个
What do you have to say about it? - This.
它会告诉你所有事情
This says it all.
1942年起，汉斯和他的朋友们 就开始帮助犹太人寻找避难所
From '42 onwards Hans and his friends helped jews to find shelter.
通常都是他的病人
Usually his own patients.
还有银行家玛登和 律师基斯的客户们
And clients of Maarten, the banker. And Kees who was a lawyer.
汉斯对于他们有多少钱 藏在哪里都一清二楚
Hans knew, how much money they had and where they were hiding.
看，斯马尔写的那些名字： 维茨曼，豪特，范·维特森
Look. The names that Smaal wrote down: Weiszman, Goud, van Witsen.
他们都曾经来找过斯马尔取钱 以便逃到比利时
All those men came to him for their money in order to flea to Belgium.
根据红十字会提供的信息 他们谁也没有成功逃出
According to the Red cross. None of them ever made it.
都是被诱骗到俾斯伯士河上 然后被屠杀和掠夺的
Lured to the Biesbosch and then murdered and robbed.
- 这里，我父母 - 他们也是汉斯的病人？
Here, my parents. - Were they patients of Hans?
不是，但我弟弟得了急性阑尾炎
No, but my brother got an acute appendix problem.
我父母去求助斯马尔 他告诉他们去找汉斯医生
They asked Smaal, for help, who sent in Doc Hans.
这里写着： 阿克斯曼医生拜访斯坦恩
It says here: 'Dr A. visits Stein.'
我们这位“善良的兄弟” 就给他做了手术
Our good samaritan even operated him
不错了，要知道他根本 不是外科医生
Not bad, he wasn't even a surgeon.
然后他告诉了富兰肯 把他们都出卖了
Then he called Franken and turned them in.
富兰肯让范·亨去设计诱骗 2天后他们就都死了
Franken had van Gein turn up and 2 days later they were dead.
我不明白，汉斯他…
I don't understand. Hans…
- 你知道他去年被捕的事情吗？ - 不知道
Did you know he got arrested last year? - No?
幸运的是，德国人总是 把所有文件拷贝15份
Thank God, the germans always made 15 copies of everything.
这是德国人的正式逮捕令 看
This is the official german arrest sheet. See.
汉斯·阿卡斯曼医生 1944年2月19日被捕
Dr. H Akkermans, arrested 19.02.1944
签名：富兰肯
Signed: G. Franken.
3周后斯马尔记载： 阿卡曼斯医生，因证据不足被释放
3 weeks later Smaal wrote down: Dr. A. got out, due to lack of proof.
他和富兰肯做了交易
He made a deal with Franken.
混蛋！
The bastard.
- 他居然杀了自己的人 - 基斯，玛登，每个人
He had his own people killed. - Kees, Maarten, everyone.
这样就不会有人问 他们的犹太客户都到哪里去了
So no one could ask where there jewish clients had been.
- 你逮捕他了吗？ - 没有，他消失了
Did you arrest him? - No, he vanished.
消失的无影无踪了 屋子是空的
In thin air. His house is empty.
- 我们刚从他那里来 - 那些装满掠夺物的箱子也不见了
We just came from there. The suitcases with the loot are gone.
葛本？
Gerben?
好的
Yes.
我们要回去了 我已经向各检查站发了汉斯的汽车牌号
We have to get back. I telexed Hans' licence plate to all the checkpoint.
上尉，我想留在葛本这里
Captain… I'll stay with Gerben.
＂格林奇万岁，女王万岁＂
# oranje boven oranje boven, leve de koningin
看，这是汉斯的吉普车
Look. That's Hans' Jeep.
灵车不见了
The hearse is gone.
- 他想溜走 - 他会去哪里？
He's trying to sneak away. - Where can he go to?
我猜是比利时，但是上尉说 他们正在检查各个路卡
Belgium, I think. But the captain said, they're checking all the road blocks.
你来开车
You drive.
我给战地保安部打电话
I'll call Field security.
那离我们这不远 不用了，谢谢
That's not far from here. No, thanks.
一封锁站刚看到一辆灵车 正向荷兰的迪普驶去
A hearse has been seen near a blockade in the direction of 't Hollands Diep.
前面，前面向右拐
Here, turn right.
- 证件 - 但我刚被检查过啊
Papers. - But I have just been checked.
快
Let go.
放手
威利？
Willi?
- 快，到后面去 - 威利，发生什么事了？
Quick, to the back. - Willi, what's happening?
发生什么事了，该死的！
What's happening, goddammit?
是谁？艾莉丝？ 艾莉丝，是你吗?
Who are you? Ellis? Ellis, is that you?
不要这样做，该死！
Don't do it. Goddammit.
该死的，让我出去 艾莉丝？
Goddammit, let me out. Ellis?
艾莉丝，不要啊 艾莉丝
Ellis, please don't. Ellis.
让我出去，艾莉丝，求求你了 我们可以谈谈
Let me out, Ellis, please. We can talk about this?
艾莉丝，你看
Ellis, look.
都给你，珠宝，金条 我这里还有更多
All for you. Jewelry. I've got more. Jewels. Gold.
给，美元 拿着
American dollars. Take it.
只要你打开棺材，艾莉丝
Just open the coffin, Ellis.
你在做什么啊？
What are you doing?
艾莉丝？该死
Ellis? Goddammit.
艾莉丝，你在干吗？
Ellis, what are you doing?
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
艾莉丝？
Ellis?
艾莉丝？不要！该死
Ellis? Don't Goddammit.
艾莉丝
Ellis.
不要这样 我和这事无关
Don't. I have nothing to do with this.
打开它，该死 让我出去！
Open it. Goddammit. Let me out. Goddammit.
不要，不要！
I want to… Don't… Don't
该死
Goddammit.
艾莉丝，不要
Ellis? Don't
不要这样！艾莉丝？
Don't Ellis?
听我解释，亲爱的
Let me explain, honey.
让我..
Let me…
该死的，你这臭婊子！
Goddammit. You dirty whore.
我会抓住你的，婊子 肮脏的妓女
I'm going to get you, bitch. Dirty kraut whore.
我会抓住你的 你死定了
I'm going to get you. You're going to die.
我们本该早打开棺材了
We should be opening his coffin, by now.
是的，我们是该
Yeah, we should.
怎么处理这些钱财呢？
What do we do with the money?
不属于我们
It's not ours.
不属于任何人
It's nobody's
是属于死去的那些人的
It belongs to the dead.
他终于安静了
He's silent now. At last.
似乎是永远地安静了
Seemed like an eternity.
妈妈
Mummy.
嗨，亲爱的
Hi, sweethearts.
- 你去哪儿了？ - 我就在这儿啊
Where were you? - I was here.
- 你在这儿想什么呢？ - 过去的事情
What were you thinking about? - About the past.
［凯法斯坦恩 - 集体农庄 以二战犹太遇难者基金创建］
…………
谢谢观赏